<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
	<eu> 
		<info linguagem="both" titulo="Sim">David Alexandre Fonseca do Canto</info> 	
		<info linguagem="pt">Nasci na cidade do Cartaxo em 1978 mas acabei por vir viver para Almada na margem sul do tio Tejo e a trabalhar como Analista / Programador de Cobol para uma consultora internacional em Lisboa.</info> 
		<info linguagem="pt">Apaixonado por fotografia, musica e tecnologia. Acabei por ter como hobies inicialmente a musica atravez da guitarra, mais tarde um pouco de piano (muito pouco) e eventualmente a fotografia. A tecnologia envolve todas estes elementos assim como o meu trabalho cono Analista / Programador.</info>
		<info linguagem="en">I was born in the city of Cartaxo in 1978 but ended up living in Almada on the south bank of Uncle Tejo and working as a Cobol Analyst / Programmer for an international consultant in Lisbon. </info>
		<info linguagem="en">Passionate about photography, music and technology. I ended up having music as a hobby through guitar, later on a little piano (very little) and eventually photography. Technology involves all these elements as well as my work as an Analyst / Programmer.</info>
		
		<info linguagem="pt">Fotograficamente interesso me por Fotografia de concertos que me permite unir a musica com a fotografia e fotografia de paisagens que me permite afastar me um pouco da confusão do dia a dia e encontrar algum equilibrio. Também já fiz alguns nús e retratos.</info>
		<info linguagem="pt">Estou disponível para trabalhar em projetos fotográficos ou como assistente.</info>
		
		<info linguagem = "en">256 / 5000
Resultados da tradução
Photographically I'm interested in Concert Photography that allows me to combine music with photography and landscape photography that allows me to get away from the confusion of everyday life and find some balance. I have also done some nudes and portraits.</info>
		<info linguagem = "en">I am available to work on photographic projects or as an assistant. </info>
		
		<info linguagem="pt" titulo="Sim">Workshops de fotografia frequentados:</info>
		<info linguagem="pt"> - Workshop de técnica fotográfica no Instituto Português de Fotografia (IPF)</info>
		<info linguagem="pt"> - Workshop de composição no Instituto Português de Fotografia (IPF)</info>
		<info linguagem="pt"> - Workshop Fotografia Nudez, Estética e Expressão por João de Castro no Instituto Português de Fotografia (IPF)</info>
		<info linguagem="pt"> - Workshop Fotografia Noturna da Photo-Nature</info>
		<info linguagem="pt"> - Workshop Photoshop no Instituto Português de Fotografia (IPF)</info>
		<info linguagem="pt"> - Workshop da IPF sobre fotografia de estúdio no Instituto Português de Fotografia (IPF)</info>
		 
		<info linguagem = "en" titulo="Sim">Photography workshops attended: </info>
		<info linguagem = "en"> - Photographic technique workshop at the Portuguese Institute of Photography (IPF) </info>
		<info linguagem = "en"> - Composition workshop at the Portuguese Institute of Photography </info>
		<info linguagem = "en"> - Nude Photography, Aesthetics and Expression Workshop by João de Castro at the Portuguese Institute of Photography </info>
		<info linguagem = "en"> - Photo-Nature Night Photography Workshop </info>
		<info linguagem = "en"> - Photoshop Workshop at the Portuguese Institute of Photography </info>
		<info linguagem = "en"> - Workshop on studio photography at the Portuguese Institute of Photography </info>

	</eu>
